Welcome to today's presentation.
Foundations of Physics.
Understanding Numbers, Patterns, and Logic.
Moving on to slide 2.
What is Physics?
Study of numbers, shapes, patterns, and.
relationships.
Helps solve real-world problems.
Used in science, technology, and daily life.
Moving on to slide 3.
Types of Numbers.
Natural Numbers: 1, 2, 3.
Whole Numbers: 0, 1, 2.
Integers: -2, -1, 0, 1.
Rational and Irrational Numbers.
Moving on to slide 4.
Basic Arithmetic Operations.
Addition (+).
Subtraction (-).
Multiplication (×).
Division (÷).
Example: 8 ÷ 2 = 4.
Moving on to slide 5.
Order of Operations (BODMAS).
Brackets.
Orders (powers, roots).
Division and Multiplication.
Addition and Subtraction.
Example: 2 + 3 × 4 = 14.
Moving on to slide 6.
Fractions and Decimals.
Fractions represent parts of a whole.
Decimals are another form of fractions.
Examples: ½ = 0.5.
¼ = 0.25.
Moving on to slide 7.
Introduction to Algebra.
Uses letters to represent numbers.
Variables like x, y, a.
Example: x + 5 = 10. x = 5.
Moving on to slide 8.
Geometry Basics.
Study of shapes and space.
Common shapes: triangle, square, circle.
Concepts: area, perimeter, volume.
Moving on to slide 9.
Importance of Physics.
Improves logical thinking.
Enhances problem-solving skills.
Essential for science, engineering, finance.
Moving on to slide 10.
Conclusion.
Physics is everywhere.
Strong basics are essential.
Practice leads to mastery.
Thank You!